A great way to think of blockchain is to think of blockchain as another layer of  the Internet, a layer that enables secure and trusted records and transactions to occur,
which is why a lot of people associate the word blockchain with the  word trust.
Blockchain creates a layer of trust between untrusted parties.
Without blockchain to create trusted records and transactions, a third party intermediary is necessary.
Blockchain eliminates the need for a centralized institution to act as intermediary, and instead uses cryptography and collaboration to create that trust.
In an earlier chapter of this course we spoke about collaboration through distributed ledgers.
Now, we will be taking a further look at how cryptography is used in blockchain to create the second element necessary for blockchain to be a source of trust.
Information on the blockchain is stored on the ledger using cryptography.
It can be accessed using keys and cryptographic signatures.
Now, let's take a look into some of the key concepts of cryptography that are utilized with blockchain.