And so, why were Bitcoin and Ethereum created? What problems do they solve?
So, Bitcoin was first launched in January of 2009, as a response to the global financial crisis at the time.
Part of the motivation for the system was to be able to transfer value over the internet, without an intermediary.
So, one of the biggest inventions and problems that it solved was that of the &#39;double spend&#39; problem.
So, Bitcoin, in fact, is programmable money.
Ethereum, on the other hand, was created as a response to Bitcoin.
While Bitcoin is focused upon transferring monetary value between parties, it has a very limited programming language.
Ethereum, on the other hand, uses a more expansive set of programming languages and tools to allow for many other types of programs and applications.
The core invention of Ethereum is it&#39;s EVM, or Ethereum Virtual Machine.
The EVM runs on the Ethereum network, and it runs a Turing-complete software.
So, Vitalik Buterin is the person who wrote the white paper for Ethereum.
Some of its key features include the immutability of data, that unauthorized users cannot make changes to that data,
the Ethereum development platform is designed to make corruption and tamper proof applications,
the secure apps are sent decentralized and secured with cryptography,
and they&#39;re protected against hacking attacks and fraudulent activities,
and lastly, it&#39;s designed with zero downtime.
That is because the applications on the network are decentralized, and on many, many machines,
if some of those machines go down, the Ethereum network maintains a stable state of the Ethereum network.